[Music]
so
in many places around the world rainfall
is a given
it comes and goes without being much of
an event
but here in my home we celebrate the
rainfall
knowing we will soon go months with
barely any the land will become parched
and dry and prone to wildfires
[Music]
so
it is shortly after the rainfall that a
very elusive but delectable life form
appears on the forest floor
they are known as morels and often grow
in disturbed areas or ones that have
experienced wildfires
they're absolutely delicious and very
different from the mushrooms you usually
see
in the stores
[Music]
i mentioned this once before one of my
greatest fears
is fire i've experienced a home fire
and it is terrifying when i shared this
with a friend they wondered why i would
move to a place that regularly
experiences wildfires
i suppose my answer is because sometimes
the benefits of a decision
far outweigh the risk i am so happy here
and no matter what happens i wouldn't
want to be anywhere else
[Music]
when i was a teenager i was living in
cuba during hurricane sandy
when i lived on the coastline we feared
tsunamis and earthquakes
wherever we went there was risk and here
it is no different
as tourist season comes around i become
a little more anxious
knowing that many non-locals either
unaware or not concerned with safety
and will light campfires even though
they are prohibited
the smoke jumpers are also vigilant and
my town prepares accordingly
[Music]
we water the grass around our homes and
put together a box of valuables
in my box i put all my documents and pet
supplies and
some of my favorite paintings and books
i try to be practical and only take what
is needed or most important to me
at any point we could lose everything
the memory of fires is everywhere in my
valley where miles of dead trees stretch
across hillsides
but to dwell on fear and worry won't
resolve the problem
instead i let those emotions take hold
of my heart for a few minutes
hold them there and respect that this is
something that is on my mind
then i try to force myself to let it go
and instead turn to asking myself
what can i do the answer is usually to
donate to my local nature conservancy
and as a teacher we would invite smoke
jumpers to visit our classrooms
and speak to our children it is hard for
me to remember sometimes but
there are so many proactive things to do
instead of worry
in our world right now it is easy to see
things through the eyes of negativity
and cynicism
but i will always believe that that
feeds despair instead of cultivating
hope and action and unity
even as i accept the possibility that
the fires may take away what i love
i know that i cannot live fearing what
may or may not happen
instead i look to nature and see that
while i waste time worrying
that it may be destroyed it is thriving
and abundant and alive
with wildfires come new plants and
undergrowth that feed the animals
a variety of plants that thrive in ashy
soil
and of course delicious mushrooms
in the midst of destruction i try to see
the hope
being rebuilt and of course enjoying the
delicacies that nature has to offer
i hope you have a lovely day or night
[Music]
so
do
[Music]
you